urbantoronto.ca 2012-09-19

# Privacy Policy | Urban Toronto

Privacy Policy

Chart Communications Inc. Privacy Policy

1\. General Principles

Chart Communications Inc. (“Chart”) is committed to preserving and safeguarding your right to privacy. Chart adheres to the requirements of the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (“PIPEDA”). PIPEDA regulates the manner in which Chart collects, uses, discloses and otherwise manages your personal information. By submitting your personal information through the Website, you agree that Chart may collect, use and disclose your personal information as set out in this Privacy Policy. Chart may, in its sole discretion, modify the Privacy Policy at any time with or without notice to you. The revised Privacy Policy shall be posted on the Chart website located at [www.urbantoronto.ca](http://urbantoronto.ca/) and every other Chart website (individually and collectively, the “Website”). You should review the Privacy Policy on a regular basis for any such changes. You agree that your continued use of the Website after the revised Privacy Policy has been posted constitutes your consent to such revised Privacy Policy, and to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in the revised Privacy Policy. The Website may contain links to other non-Chart websites. Chart is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other websites.

2\. Information We Collect

Chart may collect the following types of information about you: your name, address, home telephone number, mobile telephone number, credit card number, e-mail address, date of birth, gender and any facts that Chart deems to be reasonably necessary for the purposes of completing a transaction with you or to otherwise communicate with you (for example, Chart may also collect facts relevant to your participation in a contest, or facts relevant to a complaint made by you).

Consent.

In addition to your agreement above to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy, as amended from time to time, Chart will obtain your consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information at the time personal information is collected. Chart will make reasonable efforts to ensure that when personal information is collected that you understand why it is collected. Chart will seek a form of consent that is appropriate to the sensitivity of the information collected.

Limiting the Collection of the Personal Information.

Chart will limit the collection of personal information to that which is required to provide the necessary service or conduct the necessary activity and will only collect personal information through fair and lawful means.

Withdrawal of Consent.

You may withdraw your consent to the collection, use or disclosure of personal information at any time subject to any specific contractual commitments that you have made with Chart in respect of your personal information and the requirement for you to provide reasonable notice to us.

3\. Use of Cookies and IP Addresses

A cookie is a message that is sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. Most Internet sites use cookies. You can set your browser preferences to reject all cookies but then you will not be able to participate in most customized services, and you may be required to repeatedly log in to participate in various services, promotions, or product offerings. Cookies make your experience easier by saving your preferences and passwords.

We also use cookies that contain no personal information at all. These cookies help us estimate our audience size, determine which areas of the Website are the most popular, and serve targeted advertising. Third party advertisers and our ad server may set and access their cookies on your computer in accordance with their own privacy policies.

Some parts of the Website use cookies to collect information about visitors' use of the Website and to facilitate return visits. Information collected about user activity may be done in partnership using a 3rd party tracking tool. The information collected from cookies is tracked to enhance security and to improve the functionality of the Website by avoiding duplicate data entry, facilitating navigation, and increasing the relevance of content. Cookies on the site may collect the following information: a unique identifier, user preferences and profile information used to personalize the content that is shown, and membership information to access the Website services. Some cookies used by the Website may remain on the user's computer after they leave the Web site.

Most browsers can be configured to reject cookies or alert you when cookies are being sent. Keep in mind that if you refuse cookies, it is possible that some portions of the Website may not function exactly as intended.

IP Address.

Chart may also collect IP addresses for the purposes of systems administration or to report information in aggregate form to our advertisers (e.g. how many visitors logged in to the Website). An IP address is a number that is assigned to your computer automatically when you use the Internet. When you visit a particular the Website web page, our servers log your IP address. Your IP address is not linked to anything personally identifiable.

4\. Security Safeguards

Chart understands the importance of protecting your personal information and will implement safeguards to protect personal information against unauthorized access including the use of the latest Internet security protocols to protect personal information collected through the Website. However, you should be aware that the Internet is not a secure medium. Therefore, Chart does not represent or warrant the complete security of the personal information provided by you to Chart through the Website. You understand that you are transmitting such information to Chart at your own risk.Employees of Chart who will be involved in the collection of personal information will be educated with respect to the importance of maintaining the confidentiality of personal information.Chart will use care in the disposal and destruction of personal information in order to prevent unauthorized parties from gaining access to the information.

5\. Use of Personal Information

Chart uses your personal information for one or more of the following purposes:

(a) To provide the product, service or information you requestedIf you are a customer of our publication, we use your name and address (postal and/or e-mail) in order to deliver the product, service or information you requested and to follow up with you about the transaction (i.e., send a bill, notify you that your subscription is expiring, etc.). If you enter into a contest offered through the Website or printed publications, we use your personal information to administer the contest on our own behalf or on behalf of our sponsors.

(b) To process paymentYour credit card number for pre-authorized payments is used only for processing payments and for presenting you with payment options - not for marketing purposes.

(c) To send you informationFrom time to time we may send you further information about the Website or the publication, its offers, or other products produced under its name.

(d) To respond to complaints from youWe may use your personal information to identify you and respond to any complaints that you may make to us.

(e) Other purposesIn addition, from time to time, we may use your personal information for the following purposes:· to detect and protect Chart and other third parties against error, fraud, theft and other illegal activity, and to audit compliance with Chart policies and contractual obligations;· to understand your needs and preferences, including to contact and communicate with you and to conduct surveys, research and evaluations;· for any other purpose we may indicate to you from time to time. We will provide you an opportunity to “opt out” of any such other purposes.

6\. Disclosure of Personal Information

Your personal information will not be used to place you on any mailing lists, except with your prior consent. Under no circumstances will we sell our customer lists or rent your personal information to third parties. However, from time to time Chart may offer you the opportunity to respond to an “opt in” solicitation to receive marketing information from other carefully selected organisations and partners by email, telephone and/or SMS. Chart will only pass on these details if you opt in. Chart takes all measures possible to ensure that the contact you receive will be from reputable organisations. Chart however cannot accept any responsibility for use of the data once it has been passed on and is no longer within Chart’s control.

7\. Accuracy and Retention of Your Personal Information

Chart will take all reasonable steps to update or correct your personal information when necessary.

Chart will keep your personal information only as long as necessary for the identified purposes or as required by law.

8\. Providing Access to Personal Information

Upon your written request and subject to the exemptions stipulated by law, Chart will inform you of the existence, use and disclosure of your personal information and provide you with access to that information. You may be required to provide sufficient information to permit Chart to provide an account of the existence, use and disclosure of the information.

Chart may charge a reasonable administration fee ($15) for providing access to the personal information in accordance with your request. Chart will respond to the request for personal information within thirty (30) days of receipt of your request, and if Chart is not able to produce the information within this time frame, Chart will provide an explanation and will indicate when the information will be produced.

9\. Inquiries or Complaints

Chart is responsible for personal information under its control and has designated a Privacy Officer who is accountable for Chart’s compliance with this Privacy Policy and PIPEDA. If at any time you have any questions or complaints about this Privacy Policy or your personal information and how it is being used, collected or disclosed (including if you wish to request to update or correct any personally identifiable information you have provided), or you wish to withdraw your consent to “Use of Personal Information”, please do not hesitate to contact us via our form at [http://urbantoronto.ca/contact/news](http://beta.urbantoronto.ca/contact/news)[ ](http://chartattack.com/contact)or write to us at:

Chart Communications Inc.  
2200 Yonge Street, #910  
Toronto ON M4S 2C6  
CANADA

Phone: 416.363.3101   
Fax: 416.363.3109
